

SCIENTIST · COMPUTER SCIENTIST

Girona, Spain

🖸 wilberquito | in wilberquito | 🏕 wilberquito.github.io | 🗗 typingwil@gmail.com | 🗆 (+34) 698-40-53-59

"The best way to predict the future is to create it."

About

I am a nerdy individual that takes genuine pleasure in providing intelligent solutions, whether through general Artificial Intelligence or data-driven approaches with Machine Learning and/or Statistics. My expertise lies in Natural Language and Computer Vision.

My hobbies are extensive, but I can share with you that in my free time, I am interested in developing personal projects, reading research papers, and engaging in physical sports as much as I can. Recently, I've been enjoying volleyball and dancing.

Education

MSc. in Data Science 🗞 GIRONA, SPAIN

University of Girona SEP. 2022 - SEP. 2023

 Studies focused on advanced skills in analyzing and deriving insights from data using statistical and machine learning methods.

BEng. in Computer Science 🗞 GIRONA, SPAIN

University of Girona SEP 2017 - JUN. 2022

- Engineering degree recognized for its excellence by the Catalan Agency for Universities.
- I take pride in my accomplishment of attaining excellence in the final degree project, which entailed the creation
 of an open-source video game.

Experience _____

Data ScientistBarcelona, Spain

Citibeats SEP. 2023 - MAR. 2024

- Conducted topic modeling pipelines, anomaly detection events with explainability to comprehend phenomena within time series, and clustering solutions for the identification of relevant groups.
- Created private Python libraries, web-hook services, and deployed trained models in private registers.
- Provided technical support for previous company projects, i.e., fixing bugs, adding features, and re-fitting models.
- · Researched and implemented fast experiments, documenting the process for reproducibility and its results.
- I was in charge of defining the working framework in the Data Science team, i.e., defining the tools for research, development and deployment.

Associate Assistant Professor Girona, Spain

University of Girona, Department of Computer Science (IMAE)

- My responsibilities included overseeing lab sessions in order to instruct students in functional and logic programming, correct lab projects, and supervise exams.
- · Established a knowledge-sharing repository for students, which nowadays is being manteined as forked project.

Computer Vision Research (Intern)

GIRONA, SPAIN

Accenture SL

DEC. 2022 - AUG. 2023

FEB. 2023 - AUG. 2023

· Created and open source CAD platform for detecting Melanoma based on Convolutional Neural Networks.

Data Engineer GIRONA, SPAIN

Nexus Geographics

SEP. 2021 - SEP. 2022

- Significantly contributed to the development of a concurrent framework designed to capture, map, and store data from diverse sources.
- Created and manteined API micro-services to injest and serve data.
- Ensured data consistency across multiple databases.
- Designed and developed interactive web applications to visualize on-demand and streaming data.
- Provided training to new team members on the primary technologies utilized in the projects and offered problemsolving support.

WILBER B. QUITO · CURRICULUM VITAE

Software Engineer GIRONA, SPAIN

SUNSET Technologies ABR. 2020 - SEP. 2021

- Designed and developed a wide range of Restful APIs.
- Created interactive web applications for the healthcare sector, taking responsibility for building modules including authentication, hospital bed administration, external hospital services, and more.

Skills

ML & Data Tools PyTorch, Scikit-Learn, Hugging Face, Pandas, SQL, Kafka, and more.

MLOps / DevOps MLFlow, W&B, Docker, GitHub Actions, and Git.

FrameworksFastAPI, Flask, Spring Boot, Svelte, Angular, and more.LanguagesPython, R, Haskell, Scala, Java, JS, C++, and more.WorkflowJupyter Notebook, Neovim, Linux, GitHub and GitLab.

Cloud AWS and Google Colab.

Languages

English C1 not certified
Catalan Bilingual
Spanish Native Speaker

Relevant Online Courses_

Udemy Spark and Python for Big Data with PySpark

Kaggle Python, Intermediate Machine Learning, Advanced SQL

University of Helsinki Intermediate Funtional Programming, Advanced Functional Programming

References_

Prof. Dr. Mateu Villaret **№** Professor at University of Girona mateu.villaret@udg.edu Prof. Dr. Gustavo Patow Professor at University of Girona gustavo.patow@udg.edu Quim Dalmau **%**Tech Lead at Citibeats
jdalmaut@gmail.com